<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Everyday Ethics and Quotidian Quandaries for Computer Scientists</title>
    <link>https://csethics.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Everyday Ethics and Quotidian Quandaries for Computer Scientists</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://csethics.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignments for Week 2</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/week2assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/week2assignment/</guid>
      <description>Lead: Team 1; Blog: Team 4
Reading assignment: (for everyone)
 Ruha Benjamin, Race After Technology, Introduction and Chapter 1 John McWhorter, &amp;lsquo;Racist&amp;rsquo; Technology Is a Bug—Not a Crime, Time Magazine, 12 September 2016  Optional additional readings:
 Aylin Caliskan, Joanna J. Bryson, Arvind Narayanan. Semantics derived automatically from language corpora contain human-like biases, Science, 14 April 2017. Latanya Sweeney. Discrimination in Online Ad Delivery, ACM Queue, 2013.  Response assignments for Team 2 and Team 4:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Class</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/class1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/class1/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday, 2 February Slides [PDF]
Please submit this survey by 4:59pm today (Tuesday): Initial Course Survey
Reading assignment: Ian Barbour, Ethics in an Age of Technology
This is from a 1993 book based on a series of lectures Barbour gave in 1989. Barbour considers three different views of technology: (1) Technology as Liberator, (2) Technology as Threat, and (3) Technology as Instrument of Power.
Before Wednesday at 9:29pm, post a response in the Discussion Site (see details there on what your response should be).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/schedule/</guid>
      <description>The schedule details will be filled in as the semester progresses (and future weeks are subject to change, but as much as is known is documented here).
Week 1: Introduction Tuesday, 2 February Please submit this survey by 4:59pm today (Tuesday): Initial Course Survey
Reading assignment: Ian Barbour, Ethics in an Age of Technology
This is from a 1993 book based on a series of lectures Barbour gave in 1989. Barbour considers three different views of technology: (1) Technology as Liberator, (2) Technology as Threat, and (3) Technology as Instrument of Power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/update/</guid>
      <description>A draft syllabus is now posted: Syllabus. This will give more of an idea what is planned for the class, but is incomplete and likely to change before the class starts.
The Discussion forum is now open!
The semester hasn&amp;rsquo;t started, students in this class will be interested in this seminar on Monday at 4pm: Timnit Gebru: Computer Vision - Who is helped and who is harmed? Dr. Gebru has been much in the news recently, and I expect this talk will be relevant to topics we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss in the first few weeks of the class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redirect to Team Notes</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/notes1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/notes1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/resources/</guid>
      <description>Here are links to some useful resources relevent to this course. If you discover other resources you think would be helpful for students in the class, please let us know to add them here.
Other Classes This sheet, collected by Casey Fisler summarize courses on tech ethics: Tech Ethics Curriculum. Her SIGSCE 2020 paper, What Do We Teach When We Teach Tech Ethics? A Syllabi Analysis provides an analysis of these courses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>a
Overview Course Description:
Most decisions today are made by software, most of the rules of society are interpreted and enforced by programs, and much human interaction is now mediated by computing platforms that decide what people see and who they can talk to. As the people who decide what software gets written and how it is deployed, computer scientists have disproportionate power to mold society — for both good and bad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Interest Form</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/form/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/form/</guid>
      <description>This post is preserved for persistence, but I am no longer taking additional students in the class through form submissions.  If you are interested in joining the class, please submit this form:
 https://forms.gle/xZECFhH7DNYHyc6X9  ### (or send me an email on ethical reasons why we shouldn&#39;t ask students to submit information like this using a google form). I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if the course will be over-subscribed, but if the course fills up, I will be able to add a small number of additional students to the course who I will select based on these responses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/welcome/</guid>
      <description>This is the course website for &amp;ldquo;Everyday Ethics and Quotidian Quandaries for Computer Scientists&amp;rdquo;, a new University of Virginia course on ethics targeted to undergraduate computer science students that will be offered for the first time in Spring 2021. Scheduled course meetings are Tuesdays and Thursdays, 9:30am – 10:45am, starting on 2 February 2021.
Below, you can read a preliminary description of the course and about the reason for offering it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/week1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/week1/</guid>
      <description>Mary Chamberland, Ethical Principles for Phased Allocation of COVID-19 Vaccines (slides for CDC presentation on vaccine allocation)
Kathleen Dooling, Phased Allocation of COVID-19 Vaccines (slides with the tables)
Stanford Encyclopedia of Philosophy: Consequentialism
Internet in 1989
MIT Goes on the 5-year Plan, PC Magazine, 20 March 1984
First Major Usenix Spam
We Worked Together on the Internet. Last Week, He Stormed the Capitol.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>