<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Everyday Ethics and Quotidian Quandaries for Computer Scientists</title>
    <link>https://csethics.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Everyday Ethics and Quotidian Quandaries for Computer Scientists</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://csethics.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects Posted</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/projectsposted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/projectsposted/</guid>
      <description>Projects and presentations are now posted: Projects.
Congratulations on some excellent projects, many of which I hope and expect will have an impact beyond just this class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 13 Summary</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/week13summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/week13summary/</guid>
      <description>The blog summary for week 13 (End-to-end Encryption) is now posted: Week 13.
Thanks to Team 3 for writing the blog, and to Team 5 for leading!
This week, the final week of the semester, will be project presentations (see Presentations Schecule).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentations Schedule</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/presentations-schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/presentations-schedule/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s the schedule for project presentations for the final week:
Tuesday, 4 May  Justin, Julia Zoe, Jennifer, Sabrina Mike  Thursday, 6 May  Apekchha, Sophie, Rickey Emily, Kelly, Leandra Hana, Christian, Loryn Brock, Mariah, Lauren, Zachery Jordan, Saurav, Alex Wahaj, Alicia, Katie  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 12 Summary</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/week12summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/week12summary/</guid>
      <description>The blog summary for week 12 (Antitrust Mock Trial) is now posted: Week 12.
Thanks to Team 2 for writing the blog, and to Team 4 for leading!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 13 Readings</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/week13readings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/week13readings/</guid>
      <description>The readings for Week 13 (April 27 and 29 on End-to-End Encryption) are now posted: Week 13 Readings and Discussion.
The final week will be project presentations, so this is our last assigned readings and discussion!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 12 Readings</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/week12readings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/week12readings/</guid>
      <description>The readings for Week 12 (April 20 and 22 on Antitrust) are now posted: Week 12 Readings and Discussion. Team 4 has planned an exciting Mock Trial for week 12!
There&amp;rsquo;s no class tomorrow (Thursday 15 April) - hope everyone enjoys the Break Day and finds a way to make it refreshing (if you have no other plans, you may find watching this congressional hearing to be quite relaxing and reaffirming!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 10 Summary</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/week10summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/week10summary/</guid>
      <description>The blog summary for week 10 is now posted: Week 10.
Thanks to Team 1 for writing the blog, and to Team 3 for leading!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 11: Crowdsourcing</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/week11readings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/week11readings/</guid>
      <description>The readings and discussion post for Week 11 are now posted: Week 11: Crowd Workers.
Saiph Savage will be our guest on Tuesday, April 13. Thursday April 15 is a University Break Day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 9 Summary</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/week9summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/week9summary/</guid>
      <description>The blog summary for week 9 is now posted: Week 9.
Thanks to Team 5 for writing the blog, and to Team 2 for leading!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 10 Readings</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/week10readings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/week10readings/</guid>
      <description>The readings for Week 10 (April 6 and 8 on Privacy and Surveillance) are now posted: Week 10 Readings and Discussion.
Also, remember that your Project Progress Report is due on Wednesday, 7 April (4:59pm). It should be an update on your project and what you have done so far, and what you plan to do for the remainder. This should be sent as an email to me (evans@virginia.edu) with all of your teammates cc&amp;rsquo;d.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 8 Summary</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/week8summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/week8summary/</guid>
      <description>The blog summary for week 8 is now posted: Week 8.
Thanks to Team 4 for writing the blog, and to Team 1 for leading!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 7 Summary / Next Project Deliverable</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/week7summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/week7summary/</guid>
      <description>The blog summary for week 7 is now posted: Week 7.
Thanks to Team 3 for writing the blog, and to Team 5 for leading!
I&amp;rsquo;ve also updated the Week 6 post on the projects, with more information on the next deliverable:
 Project Progress Report due Wednesday, 7 April (4:59pm):  Update on your project and what you have done so far, and what you plan to do for the remainder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 8: Ethics of User Interface Design</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/projectideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/projectideas/</guid>
      <description>The readings and discussion post for Week 8 are now posted: Week 8 Readings and Discussion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 6: Project Ideas</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/projectideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/projectideas/</guid>
      <description>Here are the slides for today&amp;rsquo;s class: Project Ideas [PDF].
Your first deliverable for the project is a Project Idea Proposal due Friday, 19 March (4:59pm). It should include:
 List of your team members Purpose of your project What you plan to do What you hope the outcome will be.  You can just send this to me by email - a short plaintext email is fine that answers these four questions is fine, but feel free to include anything else you want feedback on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 5 Summary</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/week5summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/week5summary/</guid>
      <description>The blog summary for week 5 is now posted: Week 5. Thanks to Team 2 for writing the blog, and to Team 4 for leading!
 As a reminder, we have a break day on Tuesday this week, and will discuss projects on Thursday. There&amp;rsquo;s no reading assignment for this week, but you may want to get started early on the Week 7 readings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 6 and 7</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/week67readings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/week67readings/</guid>
      <description>The discussions posts for the next two weeks are now posted:
 Week 6 — Projects. We have a &amp;ldquo;Break Day&amp;rdquo; on Tuesday (March 9), so only one class next week and no assigned readings or discussion. Please read the post though, and start thinking about ideas for projects. Week 7 — Social Scoring. Note the (totally optional) scheduled Black Mirror &amp;ldquo;Nosedive&amp;rdquo; viewing party on Saturday, March 13 at 5pm.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 4 Summary</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/week4summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/week4summary/</guid>
      <description>The blog summary for week 4 is now posted: Week 4.
Thanks to Team 1 for writing the blog, and to Team 3 for leading!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 5 Readings</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/week5readings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/week5readings/</guid>
      <description>The assignment post for Week 5 are now posted: Week 5 Readings, Viewings, and Discussion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3 Summary</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/week3summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/week3summary/</guid>
      <description>The blog summary for week 3 is now posted: Week 3.
Thanks to Team 5 for writing the blog, and to Team 2 for leading!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 4 Readings</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/week4readings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/week4readings/</guid>
      <description>The readings and discussion post for Week 4 are now posted: Week 4 Readings and Discussion.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2 Summary</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/week2summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/week2summary/</guid>
      <description>The blog summary for week 2 is now posted: Week 2.
Thanks to Team 4 for writing the blog, and to Team 1 for leading our first week!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3 Assignment</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/week3assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/week3assignment/</guid>
      <description>The readings and discussion post for Week 3 are now posted: Week 3 Assignment and Discussion (note the deadlines for the discussion posts have been slightly pushed back from normal weeks).
Please see the link to the Rally Survey and submit that by Monday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Schedule</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/scheduleupdate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/scheduleupdate/</guid>
      <description>A new version of the Schedule is now posted!
It includes the planned topics for the weeks, and should be easier to understand than the original schedule.
It worked out for every team to have their top choices as topics, and I think we have a good mix of topics through the semesters. Nothing is set in stone, though, so if your team decides you want to switch your topics (without duplicating something another team is already scheduled to do), let me know and we can change things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignments for Week 2</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/week2assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/week2assignment/</guid>
      <description>Lead: Team 1; Blog: Team 4
Reading assignment: (for everyone)
 Ruha Benjamin, Race After Technology, Introduction and Chapter 1 John McWhorter, &amp;lsquo;Racist&amp;rsquo; Technology Is a Bug—Not a Crime, Time Magazine, 12 September 2016  Optional additional readings:
 Aylin Caliskan, Joanna J. Bryson, Arvind Narayanan. Semantics derived automatically from language corpora contain human-like biases, Science, 14 April 2017. Latanya Sweeney. Discrimination in Online Ad Delivery, ACM Queue, 2013.  Response assignments for Team 2 and Team 4:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 2: Views of Technology</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/class2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/class2/</guid>
      <description>Thursday, 4 February Slides for Class 2: PDF
Zoom as Unethical Software
VMRay Analyzer Report on Zoom
FTC Requires Zoom to Enhance its Security Practices as Part of Settlement, November 2020
Ethics of Vaccination
Novel 2019 coronavirus genome, 10 January 2020
Algorithms are deciding who gets the first vaccines. Should we trust them?, Washington Post, 23 Dec 2020
CDC Slides:
Mary Chamberland, Ethical Principles for Phased Allocation of COVID-19 Vaccines, 30 October 2020</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Class</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/class1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/class1/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday, 2 February Slides [PDF]
Please submit this survey by 4:59pm today (Tuesday): Initial Course Survey
Reading assignment: Ian Barbour, Ethics in an Age of Technology
This is from a 1993 book based on a series of lectures Barbour gave in 1989. Barbour considers three different views of technology: (1) Technology as Liberator, (2) Technology as Threat, and (3) Technology as Instrument of Power.
Before Wednesday at 9:29pm, post a response in the Discussion Site (see details there on what your response should be).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/update/</guid>
      <description>A draft syllabus is now posted: Syllabus. This will give more of an idea what is planned for the class, but is incomplete and likely to change before the class starts.
The Discussion forum is now open!
The semester hasn&amp;rsquo;t started, students in this class will be interested in this seminar on Monday at 4pm: Timnit Gebru: Computer Vision - Who is helped and who is harmed? Dr. Gebru has been much in the news recently, and I expect this talk will be relevant to topics we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss in the first few weeks of the class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Interest Form</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/form/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/form/</guid>
      <description>This post is preserved for persistence, but I am no longer taking additional students in the class through form submissions.  If you are interested in joining the class, please submit this form:
 https://forms.gle/xZECFhH7DNYHyc6X9  ### (or send me an email on ethical reasons why we shouldn&#39;t ask students to submit information like this using a google form). I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if the course will be over-subscribed, but if the course fills up, I will be able to add a small number of additional students to the course who I will select based on these responses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/welcome/</guid>
      <description>This is the course website for &amp;ldquo;Everyday Ethics and Quotidian Quandaries for Computer Scientists&amp;rdquo;, a new University of Virginia course on ethics targeted to undergraduate computer science students that will be offered for the first time in Spring 2021. Scheduled course meetings are Tuesdays and Thursdays, 9:30am – 10:45am, starting on 2 February 2021.
Below, you can read a preliminary description of the course and about the reason for offering it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Evaluations</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/course-evaluations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/course-evaluations/</guid>
      <description>Here is the summary report on the student course evaluations: course-evals.pdf.
Thanks to everyone who submitted an evaluation, and for the thoughtful comments.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>