<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Everyday Ethics and Quotidian Quandaries for Computer Scientists</title>
    <link>https://csethics.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Everyday Ethics and Quotidian Quandaries for Computer Scientists</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://csethics.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>class1</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/first-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/first-class/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday, 2 February Please submit this survey by 4:59pm today (Tuesday): Initial Course Survey
Reading assignment: Ian Barbour, Ethics in an Age of Technology
This is from a 1993 book based on a series of lectures Barbour gave in 1989. Barbour considers three different views of technology: (1) Technology as Liberator, (2) Technology as Threat, and (3) Technology as Instrument of Power.
Before Wednesday at 9:29pm, post a response in the Discussion Site (see details there on what your response should be).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/update/</guid>
      <description>A draft syllabus is now posted: Syllabus. This will give more of an idea what is planned for the class, but is incomplete and likely to change before the class starts.
The Discussion forum is now open!
The semester hasn&amp;rsquo;t started, students in this class will be interested in this seminar on Monday at 4pm: Timnit Gebru: Computer Vision - Who is helped and who is harmed? Dr. Gebru has been much in the news recently, and I expect this talk will be relevant to topics we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss in the first few weeks of the class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Interest Form</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/form/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/form/</guid>
      <description>This post is preserved for persistence, but I am no longer taking additional students in the class through form submissions.  If you are interested in joining the class, please submit this form:
 https://forms.gle/xZECFhH7DNYHyc6X9  ### (or send me an email on ethical reasons why we shouldn&#39;t ask students to submit information like this using a google form). I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if the course will be over-subscribed, but if the course fills up, I will be able to add a small number of additional students to the course who I will select based on these responses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://csethics.github.io/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://csethics.github.io/welcome/</guid>
      <description>This is the course website for &amp;ldquo;Everyday Ethics and Quotidian Quandaries for Computer Scientists&amp;rdquo;, a new University of Virginia course on ethics targeted to undergraduate computer science students that will be offered for the first time in Spring 2021. Scheduled course meetings are Tuesdays and Thursdays, 9:30am – 10:45am, starting on 2 February 2021.
Below, you can read a preliminary description of the course and about the reason for offering it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>